eurovision.tv 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy & Cookie Information - Eurovision Song Contest

On this page you can read the full Privacy Policy and Cookie Information of the Eurovision Live Events websites.

## Introduction

This Privacy Notice describes how the l'Union Européenne de Radio-Télévision ("UER")/European Broadcasting Union ("EBU") (acting as data controller and hereinafter referred as “ **we** ”, “ **our** ” and “ **us** ”) with registered office at L’Ancienne-Route 17A, 1218 Le Grand-Saconnex (Geneva) Switzerland and registered with the Commercial Registry in Geneva (Switzerland) under number IDE CHE 107.741.07 processes the information provided or collected via the Eurovision Live Events websites (eurovision.tv, junioreurovision.tv, youngdancers.tv, youngmusicians.tv, eurovisionchoir.tv and events.eurovision.tv, referred to hereinafter as the “ **Websites** ”).

We describe hereafter why we collect and process your personal data, on which legal basis, and how we treat the personal data which you provide us and the personal data we obtain from your visit to the Websites.

Your use of these Websites implies your acknowledgement of this Privacy Notice.

## Legal basis

We are only processing your personal data because you have given us specific consent or because such processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party. When the legal basis of the processing is consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of any processing carried out before the withdrawal of consent.

## Personal data collected

Our content is generally available on the Websites without the need to register as a user. We collect personal data relating to you (referred to hereinafter as “ **Personal Data** ”) in various ways:

  * **Registration:** However, subscription to our newsletters requires that you register and provide us your email address. Registration is governed by the Terms of use of the Websites and any additional terms as may be applicable from time to time.
  * **Public Posts** : Information you provide in public forums on our Websites and applications: some of the Websites have a comment functionality thanks to which you can post comments and a share functionality through which you may share content with other.
  * **Voting:** You may vote online via the Junior Eurovision song contest website. Such online vote implies processing of your IP address.
  * **Cookies** We may also collect certain information when you visit our Websites (also as non-registered user), through cookies, pixels and similar technologies.

## Use of Personal Data

Your Personal Data will be used exclusively and only to the extent necessary, to allow us to: · send you one or more of our Eurovision newsletters provided you have given us prior consent to do so by clicking on the subscription button. Newsletters are not meant to be available for children under 16.

  * Make available your public posts;
  * Process your votes in the Junior Eurovision Song Contest. Voting is governed by the Terms and conditions for the online voting in the Junior Eurovision Song Contest as made available on a year by year basis;
  * perform statistics on the use of the Websites;

We will not use your Personal Data for any new purposes which are as yet unforeseen in this Privacy Notice, except to comply with a legal obligation. In any event, prior to using Personal Data for other purposes, our Privacy Notice will be updated and we will inform you of the change. For consent-based activities, we will not process your Personal Data for new purposes without first obtaining your consent.

## Special categories of personal data

We will not collect or process any other special category of personal data relating to you, such as data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data for uniquely identifying a natural person, health, sex life or sexual orientation.

## Direct marketing

We will not use your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes without your explicit prior consent, except where authorised under applicable law. If at any time you decide to no longer receive commercial or promotional information from us, you may, free of charge and without providing any justification, opt out of any direct marketing campaigns and oppose future processing of your Personal Data for such purposes by sending us an email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2757554e5146445e6742455209444f) and mentioning “opt-out” in the subject line of your email. Alternatively, you may use the opt-out procedure provided in any promotional message you receive from us. Please note that opting out from receiving promotional messages from us will not prevent you from receiving information that relates to any contract you may have entered into with us.

## No automated decision-making

We will not make use of automated decision-making processes, including profiling, except where authorised under applicable law. In such cases we will inform you of the rationale involved in the decision-making, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for you.

## Sharing Personal Data to third parties and transferring Personal Data to third countries

We will not make your Personal Data available to any third party and shall not publicly disclose the Personal Data unless such transfers are based on your specific consent, necessary for the performance of a contract entered into between you and us, or when such transfer of Personal Data is otherwise authorised or compulsory by law or by order of an administration or judicial authority. We may transfer your Personal Data to the following recipients: partners involved in our events, providers of statistical insights about the use of our Websites, mailing tools used for sending our newsletters and hosting providers. Please note that whenever your Personal Data is transferred to processors or third parties located in countries outside the European Economic Area which are not considered by the European Commission to guarantee an adequate level of protection for personal data, we will ensure that appropriate measures are implemented according to the applicable national and European legislation relating to data protection. You may obtain a copy of the safeguards we have implemented or information as to where your data has been made available by sending us an email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0c7c7e657a6d6f754c696e79226f64).

## Use of cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or other device by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the website.

### General information about the cookies used

When you visit our Websites for the first time, the entry page will show information on privacy and wording regarding consent to the use of Google Analytics related cookies through a “cookie banner”. By continuing to actively use the Websites and by not actively objecting to the use of cookies, you are agreeing to our use of cookies; your consent will be stored in your browser, so that the information does not have to be repeated on every page of the Websites. Should the consent be missing in your browser (e.g. if you deleted your cookies), the “cookie banner” with privacy information will appear again the next time you visit the Websites. For further information about cookies requiring your consent, click here. We do not use cookies that require your express consent. We only use cookies which are required for technical reasons. You will find all relevant information about the cookies in question here:

**__cfduid**

Category of information stored: IP address  
Purpose: Identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and apply security settings on a per-client basis (functional)  
Related to user tracking: No  
Service: CloudFlare (3rd party)  
Retention time: 292 days  
Privacy policy: <https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy>

**_ga/_gid/_gat**

Category of information stored: Google Analytics session & IP- address  
Purpose: Analytics  
Related to user tracking: Yes (anonymized)   
Service: Google Universal Analytics (3rd party)  
Retention time: 2 years/24 hours/1 minute  
Privacy policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

**Cookies of embedded content**

Cookies may be set by third-party embedded content providers such as [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types), [Facebook and Instagram](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/), [Twitter](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies) and [Disqus](https://disqus.com/data-sharing-settings/).

### How to prevent cookies from being set

You may prevent cookies from being set by adjusting your browser settings accordingly. Indeed, most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about how to prevent cookies to be set, visit http://[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

However, in certain cases, preventing cookies from being set may cause certain features of the Websites to not work properly and some functionalities of the Websites may no longer be available to you.

### How to delete/deactivate cookies

In order to delete/deactivate all cookies from your computer, the majority of web browsers allow you to completely disable the use of cookies, or to delete cookies created by specific domains/Websites. To find out how to do it, please refer to your specific browser’s help page:

  * Chrome: <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en>
  * Internet Explorer: <http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11-win-7>
  * Firefox: [http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)
  * Safari: [https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?viewlocale=en_US&locale=en_US](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?viewlocale=en_US&locale=en_US)
  * Safari on IOS: <https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265>
  * Opera: [http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies](https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies)

You can specifically prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) for any website you visit by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB>. You may also specifically refuse the use of Google Analytics on any of the Websites by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting the Websites.

## Sharing

Our Websites offer the possibility to share content and to comment our Websites information via the most common social media platforms. We use a social plug-in to enable you to do so through “Share”/"comment" buttons. The “Share/Comment” functionality is only available for the Eurovision Song Contest Website and is not intended for children below 16. When you decide to share a piece of content through one of those platforms or to comment one of the information featured on our websites, our websites will link you to that platforms. Be advised that when you do this you are bound by the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policy of the social media platforms in question.

Only when you actively click on the respective button yourself will your web browser connect to the servers of the social network, i.e. clicking on elements and then clicking on the social network’s icon indicates your consent to your browser connecting to the servers of the social network and sending data to that social network operator, whether or not you are a subscriber of that social network.

We have no influence over the nature or scope of data that social networks may then gather. For information regarding the purpose and scope of data collection, further processing and use of data by social networks and regarding your data privacy rights and relevant configuration settings, see the social networks’ respective data privacy advisories.

## Links to third parties websites

On certain sections of the Websites, we provide links to third party websites (such as YouTube, Mailchimp) and social media platforms (such as Facebook, twitter, Instagram) which are not subject to this Privacy Notice. This may notably the case for third-party registration tools used for registering to our Newsletters or when you post comments or share content. These links are provided as a convenience to you; however please be aware that we have no control over these third parties or their websites and that they will have a different privacy notice applying to information collected from you when you are on their websites. We encourage you to read the privacy notices of all websites carefully before providing personally identifiable information.

## Storage duration

We will retain your Personal Data only as long as necessary for the fulfilment of the purposes described above or as required by applicable data retention laws and statutory limitation periods for claims

## Security and confidentiality

We have implemented technical and organisational measures in accordance with standard industry practices to ensure an appropriate level of security of the Personal Data processed. Nevertheless, security requires efforts from all parties involved. We thus encourage you to contribute to these efforts by taking appropriate security measures yourself, including by using strong passwords and keeping all user names and passwords (if any) confidential.

## Children on the Websites

The Websites are intended for all ages and for all publics. Our commenting functionality available under the eurovision.tv website is not meant to be used by children under the age 16. Such functionality is not available for junioreurovision.tv. If you are aged 16 or under, we request that you do not provide us with information relating to you or to others. Please seek the guidance of your parent or guardian before using our services. If you are under 16 and you wish to receive one of our newsletters, please ask your parents to subscribe to it for you. If you are the parent or guardian of a child who is aged under 16 and you believe or become aware that your child has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#95e5e7fce3f4f6ecd5f0f7e0bbf6fd).

## Your rights

At any time, you may exercise your right to request access to, rectification of, and, as the case may be, erasure of any Personal Data relating to you. You may also object to data processing or request a restriction of processing and benefit from a right to data portability (as the case may be), in compliance with applicable data protection law. You may do so by sending a signed request form with a copy of your ID card, passport or other proof of identity to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8bfbf9e2fdeae8f2cbeee9fea5e8e3) or by post to EBU, 17A L’Ancienne-Route, 1218 Le Grand-Saconnex, Geneva, Switzerland.

Where applicable, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time, this does not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent made prior to such withdrawal. As a data subject, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (in particular in the Member State of the European Union of your usual place of residence, your place of work or the place where the violation occurred) if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the applicable legislation relating to data protection.

## Data protection officer

We have designated a data protection officer whose contact email address is [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) You may contact our data protection officer with regard to all issues related to the processing of your Personal Data and to the exercise of your rights under the applicable national and European legislation relating to data protection.

## Representative in the European Union

We have designated EBU UER AISBL, Avenue des Arts 56, 1000 Brussels, Belgium as our representative in the European Union.

## Effective date and changes

This Privacy Notice is effective from 24 May 2018. We reserve the right, at our complete discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Notice at any time. We encourage you to check this page periodically to read the most recent version of this Privacy Notice as a continued use of this Website after the posting of changes to these terms will mean that you acknowledge these changes.

Thank you for visiting the Websites.
